<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Final Year Research Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[A scrapbook of research for William Park's final project]]></description><link>https://www.williamipark.co.uk</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:26:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Research Plan]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is an outline for areas I plan to research, and how I plan to do the research. Gamification Gamification will be an important area to…]]></description><link>https://www.williamipark.co.uk/research-plan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.williamipark.co.uk/research-plan/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is an outline for areas I plan to research, and how I plan to do the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gamification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gamification will be an important area to research, as the app will rely on it to create hooks that keep people coming back to the app. I plan to research this by researching more into Ocyalysis (I already have some experience with it from work). I’m going to look into other apps that use gamification to hook people and find out if it could be applied to what I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what motivates people and how the brain works when it comes to getting motivated will be something that requires a lot of focus. I’m going to look at the psychology behind motivation, and research the two different types of motivation (intrinsic &amp;#x26; extrinsic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning the psychology, I’ll move onto research into how to motivate through the use of UI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to launch a survey online or talk to several people about what motivates them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Habits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to look into the psychology behind what a habit really is. I’m going to look into how people have formed habits, good and bad, and how they’ve got out of them. I’m going to look at similar software like Habitica and see what they do to form habits. I’ve already bought Hooked by Nir Eyal and I’ll be reading it to see how I can get people hooked on my app. If I can get people hooked on my app, and my app gets them hooked to building habits, I’ll be doing well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll also try to get a survey launched online and talk to people about their habits and what motivates them to keep to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to look into who exactly would use an app like this. Should I be targeting a specific age group? When do people start getting concerned about their habits enough to want to correct them? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be putting together user personas to help me understand who my users would be. I’ll also analyise use cases for the app in doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-on-one “interviews” about this subject will be helpful as I can learn from people who would want to use this app, and from people who wouldn’t want to use the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll also put together an online survey to narrow down who I should focus on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to put some focus on researching how to build a community. I personally think a strong way to motivate people will be to make them feel like they’re part of community. A community that people can share their successes with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to build community features will help the app greatly I believe.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Project Outline]]></title><description><![CDATA[Project Overview Some people are creatures by habit, and some people struggle to keep habits. A habit, by definition, is something that you…]]></description><link>https://www.williamipark.co.uk/project-outline/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.williamipark.co.uk/project-outline/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people are creatures by habit, and some people struggle to keep habits. A habit, by definition, is something that you do often and regularly. This means forming a habit is no easy task without repeated focus. The problem is this repeated focus to build a habit can be hard to keep if you’re forgetful, busy, or even lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app will aim to use gamification hooks to pull people back to the repeated focus of creating their habit until the habit exists and fuels itself. Currently, my idea involves users earning virtual currency (but not crypto!) for keeping to their habits and spending that currency on rewards that users set up themselves. (But there’s no reason this couldn’t be expanded later to allow users to earn real rewards, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/sweatcoin-sweat-for-coin/id971023427?mt=8&quot;&gt;Sweatcoin&lt;/a&gt;). For example, if you kept to your diet habit 6 days a week, on the 7th day you can unlock a reward that allows you to treat yourself to a take-away. Of course, you could buy a take-away without that - but shame on that user!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pros:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will be interesting to apply gamification techniques to something that isn’t really a game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s something that would help drive me personally. And I’m sure could help other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The potential to grow the idea into something like Sweatcoin, where you partner with businesses to offer rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential for online interactivity (leaderboards, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cons:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will depend heavily on gamification. If it’s applied wrong, the app will fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has been done before. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://habitica.com/&quot;&gt;Habitica&lt;/a&gt;, but I personally think it’s really heavy handed with turning habits into a game and I think there’s potential in simplifying this idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful on mobile, but only have resources to create on Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How might it be built?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would work best if you can access the application at any time. So I believe native iOS &amp;#x26; Android would be best.  I would use React Native to build the UI, and Firebase to store user data. To aid with building a smooth experience, I might use some tools like React-Native-Interactable and Lottie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bonus that comes with using React Native is that although I only have resources to create an Android app right now, it’s easy to “port” a React Native project over to iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who will this be for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who struggle with building habits and need an extra push to stick to their newly created habit by giving out instant gratification. This could be people who are busy and need an extra reason to fit something into their day. It could be people who are forgetful about some habits, who need a gentle reminder from the app. Finally, it could be for people who are lazy who need something to motivate them toward forming a habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s the business model?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The likely business model would be to charge a small fee (£0.99-£2.99) for unlimited access to the application. There could also be a lite version that limits how many habits or rewards can be created with an in-app purchase to unlock the full version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s potential to allow users to get the app in the form of a subscription if online features were added such as leaderboards. But I personally hate subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There could also be potential in earning referral revenue from businesses who partner up to offer rewards.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello there. This is a blog owned by William Park, a student of Interaction Design, taught at Belfast School of Art. What is this blog? This…]]></description><link>https://www.williamipark.co.uk/what-is-this/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.williamipark.co.uk/what-is-this/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello there. This is a blog owned by William Park, a student of Interaction Design, taught at Belfast School of Art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is this blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is a small area of the internet for me to post my thoughts and research while creating my final project. It’s somewhat of a digital scrapbook. You could find anything here from ideas that I’ve had, to snippets from material I’ve been taking in as research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layout of this blog could change over time as I put more time into it, to keep the site’s content easy to digest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is my final project about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind that this is the &lt;em&gt;first post&lt;/em&gt; and the project idea can and mostly will change in ways, the general idea I’m working on is to build a native application that helps its users build and keep habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the idea of the project in &lt;a href=&quot;../project-outline&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>